Rahul Bollu Software Engineer - Disney

Hyderabad, Telangana - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Rahul-Bollu/dc40f5ce78045741

 \bullet Over 3.5 years of experience in implementing organization <code>DevOps</code> strategy in various

environments of Linux and windows servers along with adopting cloud strategies based on

Amazon Web Services.

• Experience in Cloud Technologies like Amazon Web Services (AWS) VPC, EC2, S3, ELB, IAM,

Auto Scaling, Route 53, SQS, SNS, RDS, Cloud Watch, Dynamo DB.

ullet Utilized Cloud Watch to monitor AWS resources to set alarms for notification, and to monitor

logs for a better operation of the system.

- \bullet Experience working with automated build platforms/continuous integration using <code>DevOps</code> architecture.
- \bullet Implementing DevOps tools like Ansible as configuration management for Continuous

Integration and Continuous Deployment with build tools using Maven on Cloud Infrastructure using AWS.

• Experience on version control tool GIT- Creating branches, tracking changes, maintaining the

history of code and helping the Developers in GIT related issues.

- Worked on Jenkins for continuous integration and for End to End automation for all build and deployments.
- Worked with Ansible as a configuration management tool, created playbooks to automate

repetitive tasks, quickly deploy applications, and proactively manage change.

• Knowledge on Docker.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Disney -

September 2014 to Present

Responsibilities:

 * Coordinate/assist developers with establishing and applying appropriate branching, labeling/

naming conventions using GIT source control.

- * Implemented the setup for Master slave architecture to improve the performance of Jenkins.
- $\mbox{\ensuremath{^{\star}}}$ Used Jenkins to implement Continuous Integration and deployment into Tomcat/Web logic

Application server.

- * Created Ansible playbooks for automating the Infrastructure, deployment process.
- * Managed clients, roles, tasks, playbooks in Ansible.
- * Deploy and monitor scalable infrastructure on AWS & configuration management.
- * Worked on making application more scalable and highly available in AWS.

 * Created AWS IAM roles & total architecture deployment end to end (creation of EC2 instances

& its infrastructure)

Environment: GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Tomcat, Docker, Jira, AWS, Ansible, LAMP

Software Engineer

https://www.indeed.com/r/Rahul-Bollu/dc40f5ce78045741?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

HCL Technologies -

September 2014 to Present

- = Coordinate/assist developers with establishing and applying appropriate branching, labeling/ naming conventions using GIT source control.
- = Implemented the setup for Master slave architecture to improve the performance of Jenkins.
- = Used Jenkins to implement Continuous Integration and deployment into Tomcat/Web logic Application server.
- = Created Ansible playbooks for automating the Infrastructure, deployment process.
- = Managed clients, roles, tasks, playbooks in Ansible.
- \blacksquare Deploy and monitor scalable infrastructure on AWS & configuration management.
- = Worked on making application more scalable and highly available in AWS.
- = Created AWS IAM roles & total architecture deployment end to end (creation of EC2 instances & its infrastructure).

Process Associate

Microsoft -

July 2013 to August 2014

Responsibilities:

- * Collect and document user requirements.
- * Design and develop database architecture for information systems projects.
- * Design, construct, modify, integrate, implement and test data models and database

management systems.

- * Conduct research and provide advice to other informatics professionals regarding the selection,
- application and implementation of database management tools.
- * Operate database management systems to analyze data and perform data mining analysis.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Science

Vaughn College of Aeronautics and Technology

SKILLS

AWS (3 years), Tomcat, Ansible, git, LAMP, docker, jenkins, Maven, Jira

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Skills:

Cloud Technologies: AWS

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows. Version Control Systems: GIT Automated Build Tools: Maven Continuous Integration: Jenkins

Scripting Languages: Shell Scripting Configuration Management: Ansible.

Container service: Docker